Ian C. Denard

1531 S. 10th St., #1, Philadelphia, PA 19147 Phone: 303-507-6725 Email: icd6907@gmail.com

Summary

Professional with a strong work ethic and the ability to problem solve with resourcefulness; including but not limited to 5 years of personnel management, 3 years classroom planning/instruction/management, thinking outside-the-box and a demonstrated history of getting results both in the military and civilian sector.

Experience

String Theory Schools

2014-Present

7th Grade ELA Teacher

Responsible for all aspects of curriculum creation, planning and delivery, classroom management, and contact with parents. In addition to these duties, it is imperative to have a full understanding of the latest trends in technology, as iPad deployment has supplemented textbooks.

- Develop curriculum from the ground up, create lessons and deliver the English Language Arts in new and innovate ways through the use of technology and iTunes U.
- Manage the participation, behavior, and work of all students assigned to my class.
- Stay abreast on new innovations in technology in order to remain relevant.

Cherry Creek School District

2014-2014

Substitute Teacher

Execute lesson plans according to specification and ensure students get quality education while in the classroom.

- Implement lesson plans.
- Tailor lessons to work for exceptional individuals.
- Manage all aspects of the students assigned to my classroom.

TAG Burger Bar 2011-2014

Floor Manager

Ensure a positive guest experience at all times, create schedules for staff, handle financials at the end of each shift, maintain a productive and positive work environment.

- -Ensure quality service to the customer and ensure they have a positive experience.
- Manage schedules, staff requests, call outs, and any issue that may arise while managing the floor.

Comcast National Accounts

2009-2011

National Account Support Representative II

Managed high speed internet accounts, both billing and technical, for teleworker employees of major corporations. During this time I also worked with the Comcast Credo Action Team in efforts to improve employee life, as well as better business practices.

- · Field inquiries regarding billing issues for individuals, as well as entire corporations, accounts.
- Develop and maintain positive rapports with the company contacts for the corporations that we served.
- Manage all accounts assigned to my care in an efficient manner.

Comcast Installation/Repair

2007-2009

Install and repair television, internet, and voice services in customers home, always ensuring white-glove service and guaranteeing the work to be above the expectations of the customer.

- Install services to customer request, no matter how difficult. Mission accomplishment was always priority number one.
- Troubleshoot and repair and technical issues with all product lines Comcast offers.
- Attend regular training to further knowledge of products that are offered.

United States Marine Corps Reserve, Corporal

1996-2002

Air Traffic Control Communications Technician (1996-2002)

Surveyed, sited, installed, inspected and maintained air traffic control communications systems. Provided technical assistance during system flight inspections.

- Survey sites and install air traffic control communications systems.
- Inspect and perform preventive maintenance for proper operation, and diagnose and repair faults.
- Provide technical assistance during system flight inspections; maintain diagnostic tapes, tools, support, and test equipment
- Train subordinates or less qualified personnel;

Education

Metropolitan State University of Denver, *Denver, CO*Post-baccalaurate Teacher Licensure in Language Arts, Grades 7-12

E. Stroudsburg University, E. Stroudsburg, PA B.A. in Sociology

Awards & Honors

Navy Meritorious Unit Commendation, Armed Forces Reserve Medal, Selected Marine Corps Reserve Medal, National Defense Service Medal, Co-presenter at CLAS Conference '11

Personal Skills

CPR, Stress management, Personnel management, Communication, Capable problem solver, Detail oriented, Resource management, Windows proficiency, Mac proficiency, Logistics, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Leadership, First aid